nookpress.com 2015-06-10

# Privacy Policy - Barnes & Noble

Effective Date: April 1, 2015

This Privacy Policy applies to personal and other information that may be collected when you interact with the Barnes & Noble enterprise, which consists of (a) Barnes & Noble, Inc. and its subsidiaries, including their respective businesses and operations (collectively, "Barnes & Noble"); (b) businesses and operations managed or operated by Barnes & Noble; (c) websites owned, operated and managed by Barnes & Noble, including each website that links to this Privacy Policy, and any digital content stores operated by Barnes & Noble (collectively, "Barnes & Noble Websites"); and (d) Barnes & Noble and NOOK devices ("Devices"), content, software and mobile applications ("Apps").

Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Barnes & Noble, and we believe that a single, comprehensive privacy policy that is straightforward and clear is in the best interests of our customers and our businesses.

To review the prior version of Barnes & Noble's Privacy Policy, please [click here](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/help/cds2.asp?PID=27344). 

**By interacting with Barnes & Noble in the manner described in this Privacy Policy at any time, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy and you consent to the application of this Privacy Policy to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of all your personal and other information as described.**

These current privacy policies and the privacy practices described herein apply to personal information previously collected from you by Barnes & Noble, Inc. and each of its subsidiaries, as well as personal information that they may collect from you in the future.

Barnes & Noble reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time, but you can be assured that, should it be necessary to do so, we will always do so in accordance with the Barnes & Noble **Privacy Principles** of Clarity, Security and Integrity. You will be notified of any material changes to this Privacy Policy which are less protective of customer information prior to such changes becoming effective. We may notify you of these changes by email reminders, by notice on this site, or by other acceptable means. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

_Clarity:_ We strive to communicate clearly about your privacy and how we handle your personal information.  
_Security:_ We follow security standards, processes and procedures that are designed to protect your personal information.  
_Integrity:_ We do not sell or rent your personal information and respect your preferences with respect to your personal information. 

Below you will find answers to the following frequently asked questions about how we collect, use and share your personal information:

  1. What is the personal information that we collect?
  2. Why do we collect personal information?
  3. How do we collect your personal information?
  4. How do we use personal information?
  5. With whom do we share personal information?
  6. How do we secure personal information?
  7. How do we respect your choices about your personal information?
  8. Whom do I contact if I have questions or concerns?
  9. What other information about Barnes & Noble's Privacy Policy would I want to know?

**1\. What is the personal information that we collect?**

Depending on how you choose to interact with the Barnes & Noble enterprise, we may collect personal information from you, for example your name, e-mail address, billing address, shipping address, phone number, credit card or bank account information, date of birth and other persistent identifiers that can be used to personally identify you. If you rent, purchase or otherwise place orders for textbooks or e-textbooks from Barnes & Noble College Booksellers, we may also collect your student or faculty identification number, financial aid number, your driver license number, information regarding courses you enroll in or teach, your program of study and graduation year. We may also collect other personal information regarding your interaction with Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices and Apps, including usage information, the items that you browse, purchase, download, read, watch and otherwise access, and your geographic location. To review Barnes & Noble's Mobile Privacy Supplement optimized for reading on mobile devices, please [click here](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/mobile/legal.asp?view=fullpolicy).

**2\. Why do we collect personal information?**

We collect your personal information in an effort to provide you with a superior customer experience and, as necessary, to administer our business. It allows us to provide you with easy access to our products and services, with a particular focus on the items and programs that may be of most interest to you. For more information as to why we collect personal information, please see the section below entitled: "How do we use your personal information?"

Your personal information also allows us to communicate with you about special offers, promotions, and other marketing programs and news that may be of interest to you. You always have the opportunity to unsubscribe from promotional emails by following the instructions included in each marketing email or by changing your preferences in your account. You may unsubscribe from mobile notifications by changing your settings in the Apps or on your Barnes & Noble or third party device.

**3\. How do we collect your personal information?

(a) Information that you provide to us

**

As a general matter, you can browse in our stores and on the Barnes & Noble Websites without submitting your personal information to us, although we may receive and collect certain personal information automatically, as outlined in Section 3(b) of this Privacy Policy, including site analytics regarding our websites, information your Internet browser automatically sends when you visit our websites, and information collected by cookies.

However, there are a number of circumstances in which you may need to provide us with your personal information. The most common of these circumstances include:

  * Making a purchase or placing an order
  * Creating an account or joining the Member Loyalty Program
  * Applying for a Barnes & Noble MasterCard
  * Using specific features of Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices and Apps
  * Contacting customer service
  * Additional Barnes & Noble Website, Device or App Features
  * Interacting with social networking sites
  * Entering a sweepstakes or contest
  * Publishing through NOOK Press
  * Signing up for promotional communications or using Invite-a-Friend or NOOK Press Collaborator emails

For your convenience, we have provided a summary description of each of these circumstances below.

**Making a purchase or placing an order**

When you make a purchase, rent or place an order in our stores, place an order online or purchase, download, rent or stream books, periodicals, movies, television shows and other digital content ("Digital Content"), you may need to submit personal information to us. 

**Creating an account or joining the Member Loyalty Program**

In order to use Devices, certain Apps and features of Barnes & Noble Websites, or to purchase or access Digital Content, you may be required to create a password-protected user account and provide us with personal information when you do so. Similarly, when you enroll in our Member Loyalty Program, we will ask you to submit personal information as part of your member profile. We will store and use this information to administer the programs and services in which you choose to participate, and as permitted by this Privacy Policy. 

**Applying for a Barnes & Noble MasterCard**

When you apply for a Barnes & Noble MasterCard, you will need to submit personal information directly to the issuer of the MasterCard. Personal information that you provide directly to the issuer is subject to the bank's privacy policies, practices and procedures, not Barnes & Noble's.

In addition, we disclose certain personal information to the issuer of the MasterCard in connection with the administration of the Barnes & Noble MasterCard program. The issuer does not have the right to use the personal information we provide beyond what is necessary to assist us or to administer this program. The issuer is contractually obliged to maintain the confidentiality and security of the personal information we provide and is restricted from using such information in any way not expressly authorized by us.

**Contacting Customer Service**

When you contact customer service, we may ask you to provide, or confirm, personal information so that we can better serve you. 

**Additional Website, Device or App Features**

From time to time we may offer or provide new or additional Barnes & Noble Website, Device or App features and functionality. Such features or functionality may request or require you to submit personal information to us in order to use such feature or functionality.

**Entering a sweepstakes or contest**

If you enter a sweepstakes or contest we offer, we may ask you to provide personal information so that we can consider your entry and, if you win, so that you may redeem your prize.

**Interacting with social networking sites**

Our Devices and Apps may provide you with the ability to enter (directly, or by authorizing us to download the information from a third party such as a social networking site or application) personal information such as contacts or lists of friends. These or related applications may also allow you to provide information directly to social networking sites including information about your purchases, physical location, or comments. However, we will not provide any of your information to social networking sites without your express consent.

**Publishing through NOOK Press**

If you elect to publish your content via our NOOK Press service, we may ask you to provide your bank account and routing information so that we can direct payments to you.

 **Signing up for promotional communications or using Invite-a-Friend or NOOK Press Collaborator emails**

If you sign up to receive promotional communications or notifications from us, we may ask you to provide personal information so that we can provide these to you.

Our Invite-a-Friend feature is located in various areas of certain Barnes & Noble Websites and within certain Devices. By clicking on 'Email' or 'Find friends from contacts' on your Device, customers can email a link to a friend which will invite the friend to view the Barnes & Noble Website page or attend the event described on that page.

The 'Find friends from contacts' feature on the Device may access the contacts you have entered into your Device in order to generate such emails. To remove yourself from these mailings, please call our Customer Service Center at 1-800-THE-BOOK (1-800-824-2665). Individuals calling from abroad should call us at 1-201-559-3882.

The NOOK Press Collaborator feature may allow you to share your content with other NOOK Press account holders so that they may view and comment upon your work. As part of this feature, you may receive email notifications from your NOOK Press Collaborators. To remove yourself from these mailings, please email NOOK Press Customer Service at [nookpress@nook.com](mailto:nookpress@nook.com).

**(b) Information automatically collected**

There are circumstances in which we automatically receive and collect information from you. The most common sources of this information include:

  * Web server logs
  * Cookies
  * Pixel tags or clear Graphics Interchange Format files, known as GIFs
  * Targeted advertising
  * Your Device or Apps you use, including geolocation
  * Wireless networks operated by Barnes & Noble in retail stores
  * Social networking sites
  * Your college or university
  * Business partners, contractors, and other third parties

For your convenience, we have provided a summary description of each of these circumstances below.

**Web server logs**

When you visit a Barnes & Noble Website, our web servers may automatically log information that your browser sends us. For example, we may receive and collect: the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet; the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the date and time you access the Barnes & Noble Website; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to the Barnes & Noble Website. We may also collect information regarding search queries run on the Barnes & Noble Website. We use this information to monitor the usage of the Barnes & Noble Websites and as necessary for our business.

**Cookies**

Like many online retailers, we and/or our third party providers use cookies to recognize you as you use or return to the Barnes & Noble Websites. This is done so that we can personalize and enhance your browsing and shopping experience. "Cookies" are small files that we place on your computer's hard drive to collect information about your activities on a Barnes & Noble Website. Cookies help us to: (1) speed navigation, keep track of items in your shopping bag and provide you with content that is tailored to you; (2) remember information you gave us so that you do not have to re-enter it; (3) determine the effectiveness of some of our and our third party partners' marketing efforts and communications; and (4) monitor the total number of visitors, pages viewed, and the total number of banners displayed. 

Browsers are typically set to create cookies automatically. You can choose to have your browser notify you when cookies are being written to your computer or accessed, or you can disable cookies entirely. If you disable cookies, however, you will not be able to place items in a Barnes & Noble Website shopping bag, and therefore you will not be able to place an order with us online. Also, by not using cookies, some Barnes & Noble Website features and services may not function properly.

**Pixel tags or clear GIFs**

We may use sensing technologies that use pixel tags or clear GIFs (which are also called web beacons). These technologies allow us to determine the effectiveness of our e-mail and advertising and marketing efforts. For this purpose, we tie the pixel tags and clear gifs to personally identifiable information. We may also collect information regarding the links within such marketing materials that you click on and purchase statistics regarding items you buy following receipt of such marketing.

**Third party web analytics services**

We work with third party service providers, including but not limited to IBM Coremetrics and Google Analytics, to help us better understand how you use the Barnes & Noble Websites. These third party service providers will place cookies on your computer to collect information such as how you were referred to the Barnes & Noble Website, how you navigate around the Barnes & Noble Website, what you purchase and what traffic is driven by various marketing methods. This information will help us to better serve you and provide you with more personalized information and product offerings. We do not allow third party service providers to collect your credit card information, e-mail address or password information. These third party service providers may only use your personal information to perform services for us and may not share your personal information with anyone else, or use it for any other purpose, except on an aggregated, non-personally identifiable basis.

To learn more about the privacy practices of IBM Coremetrics, you may review its privacy policy located [here](http://www.ibm.com/privacy/details/us/en/). To exercise your choice with respect to their collection of information on Barnes & Noble Websites, please [click here](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/help/help_cds2.asp?PID=29840).

To learn more about the privacy practices of Google, you may review its privacy policy located [here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). To disable the Google Analytics cookie and other third party web analytics service provider cookies, you can choose to have your browser notify you when cookies are being written to your computer or accessed, or you can disable cookies entirely.

**Targeted advertising**

We may partner with third party advertising networks that collect IP addresses, unique device identifiers (UDIDs), browser type, operating system, time zone, country, referring pages, and other information through the use of cookies, web server logs and pixel tags on Barnes & Noble Websites, Apps, emails and on third party websites and emails. They use this information to provide you with advertisements that are customized to your particular preferences, including for companies that are not affiliated with us. You may see these advertisements on Barnes & Noble Websites and third party websites. We may use this process to help us manage and improve the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. If you would like to learn more about the third party advertisers that may be aware of the fact that you visit Barnes & Noble Websites, and to understand your opt-out choices, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Please understand that Barnes & Noble does not control these third party cookies, and you should check the privacy policies of third party advertising networks to see whether and how it uses cookies.

**Your Device or Apps you use, including geolocation**

When you use a Device or our Apps, we automatically collect information through the Device or App when it is connected to the Internet. For example, we may receive and collect information concerning device registration, settings, usage, firmware version, signal strength, search queries, network interaction, the name of the network from which you access the Internet, the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the device you are using, unique device identifiers (UDIDs), downloads, sideloaded content, configuration, or service information relating to any malfunction of the Device or App. This may include information regarding your reading, viewing and activity behavior on such Devices or Apps, such as books or videos opened, date and time of use, time elapsed, page turns, bookmarks, annotations, customer reviews, and quiz or test answers.

In addition, to provide location-based services on Devices or through Apps, Barnes & Noble and third party application providers may automatically collect real-time geographic location information or other location-based information about you and your Device or other mobile device on which the App is installed. This information may be used to provide certain device or application functionality or to offer, provide and improve products and services.

To review Barnes & Noble's Mobile Privacy Supplement optimized for reading on mobile devices, please [click here](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/mobile/legal.asp?view=privacy).

**Wireless networks operated by Barnes & Noble in retail stores**

When you connect your computer or mobile device to wireless networks operated by Barnes & Noble at store locations, we may collect information concerning your location, unique device identifiers (UDIDs), date and time of access and information regarding your interaction with the Barnes & Noble enterprise through Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices or Apps as permitted by this Privacy Policy.

**Social networking sites**

We may provide you the ability to sign into a Barnes & Noble Website or App using a social networking account such as a Facebook, Twitter or Google account, or use your social networking accounts to share information from Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices or Apps. In these cases, as well as when you use a Barnes & Noble app on a social networking site or choose to join (or "like") a Barnes & Noble page on a social networking site, the social networking site may provide us with certain information about you, including but not limited to your contacts and other "likes". Please see the privacy policy for the applicable social networking site to learn more about how these sites share your personal information.

**Your college or university**

If you rent or purchase textbooks or e-textbooks from Barnes & Noble College Booksellers, we may also collect information about you from your college or university, including but not limited to your mailing and email addresses, class registration information and other course information. This information may be used for a number of purposes including providing our services to you and your college or university, sending postal mail and email, fulfilling orders, removing repetitive or unnecessary information from customer lists, analyzing data, providing marketing support, customer authentication, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), providing customer service and processing credit card payments.

**Business partners, contractors, and other third parties**

We may collect personal information and other information about you from business partners, contractors and other third parties. This includes, but is not limited to, instances in which you affirmatively authorize third parties to provide us with information. Such information may be collected via, but not limited to, software applications that you download or use on your Device or that otherwise allow you to interact with the Barnes & Noble enterprise.

In certain instances, you may be able to access our goods and services using a Microsoft account without first having to create a password protected Barnes & Noble account. If you are accessing our goods and services using a Microsoft account, Microsoft may share your personal information with us and we will store and use this information to administer the programs and services in which you choose to participate and otherwise as permitted by this Privacy Policy. In most cases, once you have used a Microsoft account to access our goods and services, your Microsoft account will be permanently linked to our services. Please note that use of a Microsoft account does not provide access to all of our goods and services.

If you link your account with us to your UltraViolet account, we may collect information regarding UltraViolet-enabled movies and television shows you have purchased from third party retailers. This will enable you to download or stream movies or television shows from us that you have purchased from us from such third parties. For more information, please view the [UltraViolet privacy policy](http://www.uvvu.com/privacy-policy.php).

**4\. How do we use personal information?**

Barnes & Noble uses your personal information across our enterprise to provide you with a superior customer experience and, as necessary, to administer our businesses. For example, we use your personal information to:

  * Provide you with products, services and information across the Barnes & Noble enterprise, including product and subject recommendations and other information in Barnes & Noble retail stores, through emails from our businesses, and on the Barnes & Noble Websites and online interactive communities, your Devices, Digital Content, Apps and software, and display associated content and advertising;
  * Administer our programs;
  * Provide customer service in stores, by telephone and online;
  * Conduct research and perform analysis in order to measure, maintain, protect, develop and improve our products and services;
  * Administer sweepstakes, contests, promotions or surveys and provide appropriate notifications;
  * Communicate with you about special offers, events, or new products or services that may be of interest to you;
  * Customize and enhance the Barnes & Noble Websites and advertising;
  * Make communications necessary to notify you regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues; and
  * Manage our business.

**5\. With whom do we share personal information?**

Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at **Barnes & Noble. Barnes & Noble DOES NOT SELL OR RENT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES. 

Please note that your data may be transferred to or shared with a third party as part of a sale, merger, or acquisition of Barnes & Noble or one of its affiliates (see "Sales, Mergers, and Acquisitions" below)

**.

Barnes & Noble shares your personal information with:

  * **Other entities within the Barnes & Noble enterprise**. Barnes & Noble owns and operates other operations and businesses and we may share your personal information with our other business units and operations, even if such business units or operations are sold.
  * **Partners**. We provide personal information to our partners that provide product and service offerings or technologies that we think may be of interest to you. Our partnerships may also result in products and services that allow you to publish Digital Content that may be shared with our partners. We may offer you the opportunity to opt-in to receive information from our partners, which may result in your personal information being shared with our partners. The use of your information by our partners and their vendors and contractors will be subject to the privacy policies of our vendors once such information is transferred.
  * **Microsoft**. We may share your personal information with Microsoft and its affiliates and subsidiaries under certain circumstances, including, for example, in connection with using a Microsoft account Microsoft may use your personal information to provide products and services to you related to your Device, Digital Content and Barnes & Noble and Microsoft services and products. These products and services may include, without limitation: (i) to enable purchases of Digital Content by you and provide Digital Content to you, (ii) to allow you to access, view and consume your Digital Content and provide related services to you, (iii) to publish certain Digital Content created by users and customers (as may be more fully set forth in any applicable terms or policies related thereto), (iv) to create and manage cross company user accounts and applications related to your Devices and Digital Content, including in connection with the integration between the Microsoft user and ID systems and Microsoft commerce platform and our products and services, (v) to offer joint product or service offerings, (vi) to provide customer support, (vii) to provide information to you regarding Microsoft product and service offerings, and (viii) as otherwise reasonably determined by us. Please note that any information provided to Microsoft will be treated by Microsoft in accordance with its applicable privacy policies in effect from time to time. Please refer to Microsoft's website for information related to Microsoft's collection, use and sharing of information that it obtains.
  * **Service providers, subcontractors and agents who perform services on our behalf**. We provide personal information to third party service providers, subcontractors, and agents that work under contract on our behalf to provide certain services. These third parties do not have the right to use personal information we provide to them in any way that is not authorized by Barnes & Noble. They are contractually obligated to use such information only as necessary to assist us and to maintain the confidentiality and security of such information.
  * **Third party providers of products and services**. These are third parties that provide products and services you may purchase or request from or through us. These third parties do not have the right to use personal information we provide to them in any way that is not authorized by Barnes & Noble. They are contractually obligated to use such information only as necessary to assist us and to maintain the confidentiality and security of such information. Additionally, we may provide you with the opportunity to link your account with us to your UltraViolet account. This will enable you to download or stream movies or television shows that you have purchased from us from third party retailers who are part of the UltraViolet content ecosystem. For more information, please view the [UltraViolet privacy policy](http://www.uvvu.com/privacy-policy.php).
  * **Third party membership programs**. We work with certain third party entities to help them administer their own membership or rewards programs by providing them with purchasing information about their customers who make purchase from Barnes & Noble. We disclose only the information that is necessary to make these third party programs work and to support your membership in them. This information usually includes your name and e-mail address as well as the dollar amount of the purchases made at Barnes & Noble. We require such entities to obtain your consent before we provide them with this information, which they usually do as part of their own membership or participation rules.
  * **Credit card companies**. Credit card transactions are handled by third party financial institutions and their vendors and contractors who receive credit card numbers and other personal information from us to verify the credit card numbers and process transactions. Although Barnes & Noble's treatment of this information is governed by this policy, the use of your information by the third party financial institutions and their vendors and contractors will be subject to their own privacy policies.
  * **Law enforcement officials and as required by law**. Barnes & Noble may release personal information to third parties when we determine, in our judgment, that it is necessary to (a) comply with the law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request; (b) enforce or apply the terms of any of our policies or user agreements; or (c) protect the rights, property or safety of Barnes & Noble, our employees, our customers, users, or others.
  * **Co-branded offerings**. In some instances, we may offer a service or feature that is co-branded by Barnes & Noble and a third party company. If you provide information in connection with such co-branded service or feature, that information may be shared between Barnes & Noble and the third party. Although Barnes & Noble's treatment of the information is governed by this policy, the third party's treatment of your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy
  * **Other websites operated by Barnes & Noble**. In some instances, we may operate a Barnes & Noble Website on behalf of a third party. If you provide information in connection with a Barnes & Noble Website operated by Barnes & Noble on behalf of a third party, that information may be shared between Barnes & Noble and the third party. Although Barnes & Noble's treatment of the information is governed by this policy, the third party's treatment of your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy.
  * **Your college or university**. Barnes & Noble College Booksellers may offer the ability to rent or purchase products or services through financial aid, student loans or similar programs. We may share your information with your college or university, lenders or other providers in order to process payments if you choose these payment methods. Additionally, certain Barnes & Noble Websites and Apps may collect information regarding your interaction with certain content as described in this Privacy Policy, and we may share such information with your college or university so that they may administer and improve their programs and services.
  * **Sales, mergers, and acquisitions**. If Barnes & Noble becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, restructuring, reorganization, or any form of sale or other disposition of some or all of its assets, personal information and your transaction history may be provided to the entities and advisors involved subject to a confidentiality agreement, and we will provide notice to you at your email address on file before any personal information is finally transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. Such a transaction may involve us (i) retaining the right to continue to use transferred personal information in addition to the right of the transferee to use such information, and (ii) engaging in additional transfers of personal information (including new personal information) with the transferee from time to time following such a transaction.
  * **Certain Digital Content providers** We may need to forward your name, email address, IP address, and shipping or billing address to certain content providers in connection with your order. The content providers may share this information with the applicable publisher and circulation auditors, and may use this information to fulfill your order and for other purposes. In these cases, the terms of the privacy policy of the publishers whose content you have purchased or downloaded will apply to you. If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from these publishers, you must contact the publisher directly.

**6\. How do we secure personal information?**

We take significant and appropriate security measures, including physical, technological and procedural measures, to help to safeguard your personal information and to prevent unauthorized access and disclosure. In addition, we use industry-standard technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology in the transmission of certain sensitive personal information, designed to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your personal information, and, as technology develops, we intend to take additional measures to improve security.

We want you to feel confident whenever you visit us in our stores, on the Barnes & Noble Websites, or use Barnes & Noble Devices or Apps. While we are focused on the security of your personal information and follow strict standards, processes and procedures that are designed to protect your personal information, you must remember that the Internet is a global communications vehicle open to threats, viruses and intrusions from others and so we cannot promise, and you should not expect, that we will be able to protect your personal information at all times and in all circumstances.

**7\. How do we respect your choices about your personal information?**

You may choose to opt out from receiving marketing and promotional communications from Barnes & Noble at any time by following the instructions below.

  * **For Barnes & Noble Booksellers**: At any time, a customer may choose to opt-out of the receipt of any promotional communications by clicking on the opt-out link provided at the bottom of each email and following the instructions, or by emailing our Customer Service Department by [clicking here](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/help/customer_service/morehelp.asp).
  * **For Barnes & Noble College Booksellers**: At any time, a customer may choose to opt out of the receipt of any promotional communications by clicking on the opt out link provided at the bottom of each email and following the instructions.
  * **For barnesandnoble.com** : Any account holder can opt-out of the receipt of any promotional communications by logging onto their Account and following the instructions under "Communication Preferences". If you do not have a barnesandnoble.com account, you may opt out of the receipt of such communications by selecting the link at the bottom of any promotional email communication and following the instructions.
  * **For Barnes & Noble Member program**: Any Member can opt out of the receipt of any Member program promotional communications by logging on to their barnesandnoble.com Account and following the instructions under "Change Your Communication Preferences." If you do not have a barnesandnoble.com account, you may opt-out of the receipt of such communications by selecting the link at the bottom of any promotional email communication and following the instructions.
  * **For Barnes & Noble Educator program**: Any Educator can opt out of the receipt of any promotional communications by logging on to their barnesandnoble.com Account, clicking "Communication Preferences," and following instructions under "Change Communication Preferences." If you do not have a barnesandnoble.com account, you may opt out of the receipt of such communications by clicking on the opt-out link provided at the bottom of each email and following the instructions. If no opt out link exists reply to the email with the word "Remove" in the subject line, or by e-mailing our Customer Service Department by [clicking here.](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/help/customer_service/morehelp.asp)
  * **For the Barnes & Noble Gift Card website**: Any customer of the Barnes & Noble Gift Card website who receives promotional communications can opt-out of the receipt of any such communications by clicking on the opt-out link provided at the bottom of each email and following the instructions or by sending an e-mail to [giftcardprefs@bn.com](mailto:giftcardprefs@bn.com).
  * **For SparkNotes.com** : Any SparkNotes.com customer who does not wish to receive promotional product and service communications can choose to remove their contact information from SparkNotes.com contact list by following the instructions listed on www.sparknotes.com.
  * **For Sterling Publishing** : If, at any time, you wish to no longer receive ENewsletters from Sterling Publishing Co., Inc., Lark Crafts, and/or FlashKids.com, please click on the link for opt out instructions contained at the bottom of each ENewsletter. You can change your personal information and your communication preferences when you follow [this link](http://www.barnesandnoble.com/help/customer_service/morehelp.asp).
  * **For Invite-a-friend emails** : You may choose to opt out of receiving communications from other of our customers through Invite-a-Friend features by calling our Customer Service Center at 1-800-THE-BOOK (1-800-824-2665). Individuals calling from abroad should call us at 1-201-559-3882.
  * **For NOOK Press collaborator emails** : You may choose to opt out of receiving NOOK Press collaborator emails by contacting NOOK Press Customer Service at [nookpress@nook.com](mailto:nookpress@nook.com).

Even if you opt-out of receiving promotional communications, you may continue to receive emails and notifications relating to order confirmations, back order notifications, membership information, and/or other business-related communications.

_IBM Coremetrics & Targeted Advertising_

You may choose to opt out of collection of automatically collected information, including cookies, IBM Coremetrics and targeted advertising, by following the instructions given in Section 3(b) above, or by using the functionality in your browser to reject cookies.

_Online Community Users_

Barnes & Noble provides you with the ability to access, correct, change or request deletion of the personal information in your community profile(s) at any time by following the instructions below. We will respond to all access requests within 30 days. However, you cannot currently change your profile name although you may re-register and choose a new name. To review or modify your profile information, please [click here](http://my.barnesandnoble.com/communityportal/userprofile.aspx). Please be advised that Barnes & Noble may archive information it collects on its community and visitors. Additionally, by participating in the Barnes & Noble online interactive community, and using Barnes & Noble's various interactive offerings, including, the submission of customer reviews, or participation in the Barnes & Noble Book Clubs, you agree to receive communications from Barnes & Noble, other users, and moderators related to the provision of these services.

You may access, correct or change the personal information in your community profile(s) on Lark Crafts at any time. To review or modify your profile information, log in to larkcrafts.com. Additionally, by using Lark Crafts' various interactive offerings, you agree to receive communications from Barnes & Noble, Lark Crafts, other users, and moderators related to the provision of these services.

You may also access, correct or change the personal information in your community profile(s) on SparkNotes.com at any time, except to change your username. To review or modify your profile information, log in to [SparkNotes.com](http://www.sparknotes.com/). Additionally, by using SparkNotes.com's various interactive offerings, you agree to receive communications from Barnes & Noble, SparkNotes, other users, and moderators related to the provision of these services.

**8\. Whom do I contact if I have questions or concerns?**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) or call customer service at 1-800-THE-BOOK [1-800-843-2665].

**9\. What other information about Barnes & Noble's Privacy Policy would I want to know?**

 **Policies for Minors, including children under the age of 13**

Barnes & Noble is committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations regarding the collection, storage and use of personal information of Minors under the age of 13, including the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.

Except as noted below : (i) our products and services are marketed for and directed towards purchase by adults or with the consent of adults; (ii) Individuals under the age of 18 ("Minors") are not permitted to use Barnes & Noble Websites or Apps without the supervision of a parent or legal guardian; (iii) we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register for an online account or to post personal information on the Barnes & Noble Websites; and (iv) should we learn that someone under the age of 13 has provided any personal information to or on any of the Barnes & Noble Websites, we will remove that information as soon as possible.

If we direct certain Devices features or Apps to Minors who may be under the age of 13, we require the parent or legal guardian to provide verifiable consent to such Minor's use of our products and services and our collection of personal information in connection with such use. In these cases, we require validation of credit card information already on file with us and we will then e-mail the master account holder to give notice that we have received such consent. If no credit card information is on file, or if the credit card is invalid, we will not register that you have consented. With your consent, we may collect, use and share information regarding Minors under the age of 13 consistent with this Privacy Policy. Please see the sections above for detailed information on how we do so.

If you are a parent or guardian who believes that your Minor under the age of 13 has submitted personal information or other information to us without your consent, please contact [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com). Once we verify that you are the parent or legal guardian, at your request, we will promptly provide to you information regarding what, if any, personal information we have collected about your child and how it has been used or shared. We will, at your request, remove personal information about your child from its database and instruct our affiliates and third party partners to do the same.

If you are a Minor under the age of 18, you may request and obtain removal of certain content or information posted on Barnes & Noble Websites and Apps by sending an email to [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) with ?Privacy Rights for Minors? in the subject line. Please be advised that our removal of your post(s) does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted on Barnes & Noble Websites or Apps.

**Data retention policy**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Accessing your information**

You have the right to ask us not to use your personal information for direct marketing purposes. You also have the right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies rectified. Please note that, as permitted by law, we may charge a nominal fee for information requests and may require you to prove your identity. Following a request, we will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you in our files. Please address written requests and questions about this to [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com). We will respond to all access requests within 30 days.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents to request a notice from us describing which categories of personal information we have shared with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties or corporate affiliates' direct marketing purposes within the last calendar year, and the name and address of such parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please send an email to [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) with "California Privacy Rights Request" in the subject line.

**Do Not Track Disclosure**

Certain web browsers may provide an option by which you may ask your browser to inform websites you visit that you do not wish your activities to be tracked by cookies or other persistent identifiers, commonly called "Do Not Track Signals". Although Barnes & Noble Websites are currently unable to respond to Do Not Track Signals, you may opt out of tracking activities bv following the instructions in this Privacy Policy to opt out of IBM Coremetrics and behavioral advertising.

**Important information about third party devices, ISPs, websites and applications**

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Barnes & Noble enterprise. Whenever you click on links and banners on any Barnes & Noble Website that take you to a third party website or you use, download or install third party software applications onto your Device, your use of those third party websites and/or software will be subject to the third party's privacy policies, not Barnes & Noble's. Additionally, please note that when using Barnes & Noble Websites or Apps, third party mobile device manufacturers and internet service providers (ISPs) may collect personal information about you and your use of such third party products and services will be subject to the third party's privacy policies.

In addition, our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Barnes & Noble. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Information collected from visitors from outside the United States**

If you are visiting Barnes & Noble or a Barnes & Noble Website from outside the United States and provide us with personal information, please note that your personal information will be transferred, stored and processed within the United States. Additionally, Barnes & Noble may transfer your personal information to other countries, for example because a server or third party service provider is located there. The data protection and privacy laws of other countries, including the United States, may not afford you the same level of protection as those in your own country. Barnes & Noble will take appropriate steps to protect your information.

 **By doing business or interacting with Barnes & Noble, you are consenting to the transfer, storage, and processing of your personal information to and within facilities located in the United States and other facility locations selected by Barnes & Noble. **

**Safe Harbor**

Barnes & Noble has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through uk.nook.com, www.nookpress.com, NOOK Apps and your interactions with NOOK Simple Touch, NOOK Simple Touch GlowLight, NOOK GlowLight, NOOK HD and NOOK HD+. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through third party downloadable software or at the device level.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Barnes & Noble complies with the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from, respectively, European Union member countries and Switzerland. Barnes & Noble's subsidiary Nook Digital, LLC (f/k/a barnesandnoble.com llc) has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Barnes & Noble's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

**Terms of Use**

Any dispute between you and us regarding the privacy of your personal information is subject to this Privacy Policy and the terms of use or terms of service applicable to our product or service you use, including limitation on damages, resolution of disputes, and application of the law of the State of New York.

**Contact Information**

The address for Barnes & Noble is 122 Fifth Avenue, New York, NY 10011. 

Released: April 2015  
nook-privacy-enUS-v2
